

Senior Web Developer Tech Lead

linkedin.com/in/jon-r90 github.com/jon-r Jon.Richards@outlook.com 07851 411 534

Accomplished and enthusiastic software engineer with over ten years of hands-on development experience. As a self-taught developer, I am proactive, adaptable and always ready to learn.

My experience includes contributing to a variety of commercial applications; from bespoke internal dashboards to full enterprise platforms that served hundreds of thousands of active customers.

Most recently my work has included being the tech lead for mixed discipline teams. I've enjoyed both the challenge of handling multiple tech operations as well as the mentoring of my junior colleagues. Positive and social team culture is important to me, I like to be in office where possible and I enjoy taking part in socials.

SKILLS

- Technical Leadership 3-4 years, Mentoring, Agile Training, Estimates, Solution Design, Workshops
- Frontend Development 10+ years, Typescript, React, Redux, Vue, Vite, Webpack, HTML
- Backend Development 2-4 years, Node.js, Go, C#, MongoDB, SQL, REST, GraphQL
- AWS Cloud 4-5 years, Lambdas, EC2, DynamoDB, CodePipeline, Serverless Applications
- CI/CD Practices 6+ years, Version Control, Unit/Integration Testing, Pipelines, SonarQube
- DevOps & Infrastructure 3+ years, CDK, Terraform, Architectural Patterns

EMPLOYMENT

GlobalLogic (Hitachi) - Digital Consultancy

Working on a data-visualisation product for Hitachi Energy/Rail. Aggregating thousands of points of geospatial data from a wide variety of sources (power, healthcare, rail, demographics) and unifying it for real-time analysis.

2023-Present - Technical Lead

Managed 15-20 developers to present map data in a performant, highly customisable web app.

- Led solution design & development across the product.
- Guiding frontend team to build a clean, scalable React application.
- Directing backend team (Python, Java) to optimise API performance.
- Normalising data from manual and automated entry.

Mentoring 5-10 typescript developers, ranging from bootcamp graduates to senior engineers.

- Training teams to work in a professional environment.
- Encouraging best development & delivery practices.
- One-to-one meetings to discuss personal development plans.
- Creating interactive (chocolate based) demos to make learning fun and memorable.

Sharp Gaming (Betfred) - Enterprise Gambling Platform

Working on a large-scale migration project bringing the Betfred digital system fully in-house. Now fully migrated, Betfred maintains tens of thousands of daily customers with a multi-million-pound weekly turnover.

2021-2023 - Lead Developer

Member of the Centre of Excellence team, working closely with enterprise architects on how to make the most of AWS Managed services.

- Research, design, and doc's to add future technologies (AWS, micro-frontends, progressive enhancement).
- Mentoring/supporting members across multiple projects.
- AWS Solution Design Node.js, TypeScript, CDK, ApiGateway, Lambda, S3.
- CI/CD Implementation for Micro-Frontends Jenkins, Pact testing, Docker, Webpack Module Federation.

2019-2021 - Senior Developer

A senior member of the games team, producing a service stack suitable for multiple gaming product requirements (Slots, Live Casino, Jackpots, Bingo).

- Complex gambling integrations with bespoke content management. 3rd party APIs, UKGC compliance, Responsible Gambling, KYC.
- Custom CMS focused on games content MongoDB, Express, React, Node (MERN stack).
- Frontend games integrations React, Redux, REST, UKGC Compliance.

2017-2019 - Web Developer

Part of the greenfield team setting up the foundations for a new cross-product platform (Gaming, Sportsbook, Account Management, Payment System).

- Future-proof React & Redux architecture.
- Server-Side React app (custom Express based SSR app).
- WebSocket for real-time event odds, and Node/SQL data driven sportsbook.

EDUCATION

- University of Bolton 3D Games Art, Bachelor of Arts (Hons) First Class
- Bay House College A Levels, Maths A, Physics B, Graphics C